# Nikita Ilin

 GitHub: N1KlTA | CodeForces: N1KlTA | ◀ Telegram: @N1KlT4 | ilinna412@gmail.com | ┗ +971(058)595-1239

#### **OBJECTIVE**

CS student with strong knowledge in mathematics and programming. My main interests in math are combinatorics and graph theory, in computer science I have a huge experience in sport programming, my main language is a C++ and Python as a second language (more for research). Also I have some practice in databases, low-level programming, machine and deep learning, multithreading, web technologies and other areas of CS education. My skills are ahead of my grade because I study a lot at my own. Right now I want to get more real practice in backend development.

#### EXPERIENCE

HFT NDA
Quantative researcher
Oct 2023 - Jan 2024
Quantative researcher
Dubai, UAE

- Inventing high-frequency trading models
- Research hypotheses in python jupiter notebook with using standart libraries like Pandas, NumPy and Matplotlib
- Designing and porting a test model to C++ using a special internal framework for subsequent testing and improvement

Ethflow inc.

Software engineer

Apr 2024 - Current time
Remote

- Providing a software for cryptocurrency trading
  - Working with various smart contracts
  - Designing and implementing microservices on Go language

## **EDUCATION**

High School of Economics, Moscow, Russia BSc in Computer Science and data analysis	Sep 2023 - Current time GPA: 8.07/10.0
Neapolis University Pafos, Paphos, Cyprus BSc in Applied Computer Science granted by JetBrains	Oct 2022 - Aug 2023 GPA: 8.15/10.0
Presidential Physics and Mathematics Lyceum №239, Saint Petersburg, Russia 5th - 11th grade	Sep 2015 - May 2022 GPA: 4.06/5.00
Mathematical Center at the 30 and 239 Lyceums, Saint Petersburg, Russia Additional education in Olympiad mathematics	Sep 2014 - May 2022

#### ACHIEVEMENTS

Participant NEERC (ICPC semi-final) from Cyprus ("Ungifteds" team)  2023
0000 L 4. C 1 E 14f
2000+ rating CodeForces platform 2023
Prize-winner All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren in mathematics for the 11th grade 2022
Prize-winner All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren in mathematics for the 10th grade 2021
Participant All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren in physics for the 9th grade 2019
Participant Eight educational programs of the Sirius Educational Center 2017 - 2022
Many diplomas Regional Olympiads in mathematics, physics, economics, computer science and e.t.c. 2019 - 2022
Many diplomas Prestigious St. Petersburg City Olympiad in Mathematics 2016 - 2022
Many diplomas All-Russian Euler and Maxwell Olympiads 2017 - 2019

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Main programming language:C++Other languages:Python, Go, Kotlin, Assembler, PHPWeb Technologies:HTML, CSS, JavaScriptMiscellaneous:SQL, Git, Shell, Latex

# TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Computer Science: Machine and Deep Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms, Multithreading, Computer Architecture Mathematics: Discrete Maths, Probability and Statistics, Math Analysis, Linear Algebra, Olympiad Mathematics